# BHOOMIKA.M

<u>abhoomikaa07@gmail.com</u> • 9731622516 • linkedin.com/in/bhoomikaa07 • Bangalore-70

## **Content Writer**

With 4 years of experience in creating high-impact and customer-oriented content, I have been instrumental in developing product plans, roadmaps and strategies aligned with corporate goals. I have also successfully implemented multiple products resulting in a 10% increase in revenue, as well as optimized the customer journey and increased website traffic by 25% through the implementation of product demo videos and innovative web design. My strong communication and teamwork skills have enabled me to create various successful marketing and sales materials, which have increased the product's visibility.

## **SKILLS**

- Creative Writing and Content Creation
- Website Design and Optimization
- Strategic Planning and Analysis
- Collaboration and Cross-Functional Leadership
- Copywriting
- Editorial/proofreading
- Quality Assurance
- Social Media Optimization
- Brand Tone/Style Maintenance
- Content Analysis
- Audience Insights
- Collaboration
- · Keyword research & optimization
- SEO content strategy
- WordPress & HTML
- Infographic, video & presentation creation
- Information gathering & research
- Analytics & reporting
- Storytelling & blogging
- Title, meta tag & meta description optimization

- Link building & outreach
- Content strategy & goal setting
- Brand awareness & visibility
- Search engine optimization (SEO)
- Audience targeting & engagement
- Data analysis & interpretation
- Competitor research & market analysis
- Editorial content creation & publishing
- Copywriting & proofreading
- Social media marketing & advertising
- Technical SEO & structured data mark-up
- SEO performance measurement & optimization

## **EXPERIENCE**

SR Sports, Bangalore- Content Writer

MONTH 2019-2020

- Analyzed customer feedback to modify existing and develop new product specifications to exceed market demands and position the company's products as industry-leading solutions.
- Collaborated cross-functionally with internal stakeholders to leverage financial, technical, and operational resources to maximize product benefits
- Created various successful marketing and sales materials, including brochures and technical presentations which increased product visibility across the region

## PodiumPRO- Blog Writer

MONTH 2020-2021

- Researched and wrote blog posts, newsletters, website content, white papers, press releases, and social media posts that increased online engagement and brand visibility by 25%
- Drafted and edited multiple case studies showcasing success stories that have been successfully used to acquire new business opportunities and partnerships
- As a freelancer successfully managed a team by optimizing workflow process, implemented quality assurance measures to ensure accuracy, and provided comprehensive feedback to maximize content quality

## Veave technology PVT LTD, Bangalore- SEO Content Writer

MONTH 2021-2023

- Ensured the consistency of tone and maintained brand standards across all content marketing campaigns in the form of articles, website pages, and video content
- Researched and gathered valuable information from reliable sources to produce SEO-friendly content driving 25% more viewers to the website
- Monitored and reported on analytics to recommend improvements that enhanced website visibility and organic ranking by 65%
- Crafted and optimized title tags, meta tags and meta descriptions that boosted website click-throughs on search engine by 24%
- Established link building networks to promote company content resulting in 32% more website visitors and 34% higher conversion rates
- Collaborated with content strategy team to identify targetvoice and measurable goals that improved brand awareness by 62%

#### The Dapifer, New York- Fashion Writer

MONTH 2023

- Developed content ideas and headlines that have allowed a brand to capture the attention of their target audience
- Wrote and proofread website copy for a major website relaunch, ensuring a seamless user experience and clear messaging
- Conducted extensive research on fashion topics, ensuring accuracy and credibility in all content

## **EDUCATION**

Computer Science Engg- Oxford college, Bangalore

#### **AWARDS**

- Certified- Creative Writer
- Certified- SEO Content Writer
- Certified- The Hour Of Code